Fairy Tale Endings Aren't What They Used To Be.
Happily N'Ever After is a adventure, animation,
comedy film directed by Paul Bolger.
An alliance of evil-doers, led by Frieda, looks to take over Fairy Tale Land.
But when Ella realizes her stepmother is out to ruin her storybook existence, she takes
a dramatic turn and blossoms into the leader of the resistance effort.
Der Zauberer (voice), played by George Carlin.
Mambo (voice), played by Andy Dick.
Ella (voice), played by Sarah Michelle Gellar.
Gute Fee (voice), played by Lisa Kaplan.
Rumpelstilzchen (voice), played by Michael McShane.
Freund #2 (voice), played by Rob Paulsen.
Happily N'Ever After is a 2006 animated fantasy
adventure comedy film directed by Paul J.
Bolger, produced by John H.
Williams, and written by Rob Moreland.
It is inspired by fairy tales of the Brothers Grimm and Hans Christian Andersen and
loosely based on the 1999 animated German television series Simsala Grimm.
The title is the opposite of a stock phrase, happily ever after; the name
is contracted with an apostrophe between the N and the E.
The film stars the voices of Sarah Michelle Gellar, Freddie Prinze, Jr., Andy Dick,
Wallace Shawn, Patrick Warburton, George Carlin, and Sigourney Weaver.
The film was one of Carlin's final works before his death in 2008.
Lionsgate theatrically released Happily N'Ever After in
the United States on January 5, 2007.
The film was panned by critics and grossed $38 million worldwide against a
production budget of $47 million, becoming a box-office bomb.
Despite its negative reviews and poor performance, it was followed by a direct-to-video sequel
in 2009 called Happily N'Ever After 2: Snow White—Another Bite @ the Apple.
The film explores themes of princess, dwarf,
wolf, fairy tale, bad mother-in-law.
The tone is lighthearted.